Alexander Dumouchelle

◆ Ashburn, VA

□ alexdumo@openmarch.com

ø alexdumo.com in AlexDumo

• AlexDumo

•

Summary _

I'm a software and machine learning engineer who is always excited to take on new challenges. I thrive in fast-paced environments with a dedicated team. I've worked on projects ranging from machine learning to full-stack web development. In addition, I'm also an involved teacher and performer with a love for music and education.

Education

BS James Madison University, Computer Science & Independent Scholars

- GPA 3.65 / 4.0 169 credits avg 20 credits/semester
- Minors in Music, Music Industry, and Honors Interdisciplinary Studies
- President's and Dean's List 6 of 8 semesters
- **Drum Major** JMU Marching Royal Dukes 500+ members

Harrisonburg, VA Aug 2019 - May 2023

Experience _____

Accenture Federal Services, Software and Machine Learning Engineer

- Lead full-stack developer for an internal data labeling accelerator
- Increased labeling efficiency by 80% with Python and Docker-based automation
- Trained computer vision models for image restoration and artifact classification
- Customized diverse datasets of > 300k images to train robust and flexible models
- Implemented Docker to containerize and streamline machine learning pipeline
- · Worked on three projects simultaneously, balancing deadlines and responsibility

The Cadets Drum and Bugle Corps, Administrative Staff

- Resolved and prevented logistical issues on a national tour
- Constant pressure involving a high degree of accountability and self-guidance
- Often the only person assigned to critical issues

Arlington, VA Aug 2023 - Present

Erie, VA May 2023 - Aug 2023

Independent Projects

OpenMarch, Founder and Lead Developer

- Built a free, open-source app to introduce competition in the marching arts
- Developed hands-on technical expertise and product management skills
- Led a remote team of volunteers, applying agile development practices
- Partnered with organizations and companies to expand industry adoption
- Collected user stories from 300+ designers and thousands of users
- Designed a performant SQLite database with automatic history tracking
- Bootstrapped funding through merchandise sales and marketing

GitHub Repo ☑
OpenMarch.com ☑
Aug 2023 - Present

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Typescript, HTML, CSS, C, C++, Java, SQL

Frameworks and Libraries: React, Pytorch, Django, Next.js, Node.js, Electron, Tailwind

Tools and Techniques: AWS (S3, EC2), Computer Vision, Git, Linux, Docker, OOP, Agile, RESTful APIs

Interests

Teaching: High school marching band and drum corps instructor (200+ members), private music lessons

Performing: Brass band, solo competitions, community ensembles